Satguru Saran Satsangi P.

Product Designer

Website: http://psssatsangi.com/

Email: satsangi77@gmail.com

Phone: +13177021793

Summary

Three years' experience as Product/ User Experience Designer, partnering with internal and external stakeholders to design, build, improve and expand the user experience. A proven history of creating cutting edge interface designs and information architectures for websites and mobile applications through a user-centered design process by constructing screen flows, prototypes, and wireframes.

Experience

Graduate Research Assistant (UI/UX) | Indiana January 2017- Dec 2018 University

I lead the UX team in COMET LAB, and conducted research using both qualitative and quantitative methods. Most of my projects in comet lab are from health domain.

My projects include: MIPS (Merit-based Incentive Payment System) is a web-based application to determine if clinicians are providing good care for patients in efficient way. IUSOC (IU Student Outreach Clinic) is an Indiana University website to manage volunteers who sign up to help out at its events at multiple locations.

Product Designer | New Wisdom, LLC October 2017- December 2018

I worked remotely and collaborated with development and 3D modeling teams. As a UI/UX Designer in this project, I helped the client design a new UI for their E.com website, which sells fit overs. The client wanted a Virtual Try-on in their website for their customers to try the fit overs using their webcam at home. My main responsibility was to test and integrate SDK required for Virtual Try-on in their new website.

UI/UX Designer | The Workshops

June 2014- July 2014

I worked as a team lead and UX Designer for implementing a website for the NGO, which is used for training Egyptian women in different fields. My responsibilities include requirement gathering, designing wireframes and prototyping, information Architecture, User testing and collaborating with the developer.

Skills

Design

Visual Design
Story Boarding
Wire-framing
Interactive Prototyping
Sketching
Information Architecture

Research Mothods

Affinity Mapping
Heuristic Evaluation
Usability Testing
Focus Analysis
Persona
Cognitive Walkthrough
A/B testing
Contextual Inquiry
Competitive Analysis

Design Tools

Adobe Creative Suit Sketch InVision Figma Marvel

Programming

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MySQL

Education

MS Human Computer Interaction Indiana University, Indianapolis January 2017 - December 2018

B.Tech Information Technology Gayatri Vidya Parishad college of Engineering August 2011 - May 2016

Reference

Robert Skipworth Comer, M.S.

Research Associate, Media Arts and Science Email: rscomer@iupui.edu

Sonny E. Kirkley

Director of Product/UX Design, New Wisdom

Email: sonny@wisdomtools.com